If it pleases you, Lord Megatron,
恕我直言 威震天陛下
once Soundwave discovers a means of decoding the remainder of the Iacon database
现在声波在破译剩余的铁堡密码
-- as we know he will, I would suggest the deployment of an underutilized asset.
我们知道他定能手到擒来
And what asset would that be, Airachnid?
什么资源 毒蜘蛛？
I believe that my superior tracking skills would expedite
我相信我卓越的侦查技能
your quest to recover the remaining relics.
可以加快您寻找其余遗物的步伐
Noted.
我知道了
You are a gracious audience, My Lord.
英明的决断 我的陛下
Soundwave.
声波
Remind me of her trustworthiness.
我该信任她吗？
"I believe we must consider the possibility of a future... without Megatron."
“我们必须做出长远的打算 无需考虑威震天了”
Dreadwing.
骇翼
I am at your beck and call, Lord Megatron.
随时听从您的吩咐 威震天陛下
I wish to entrust you with a task I would normally reserve for myself.
我要交给你一个本该由我亲自督办的任务
That is, if you wish to prove yourself worthy of becoming my first lieutenant.
这也是证明你能胜任副官的最好机会
That post belongs to Airachnid.
这个职位目前属于毒蜘蛛
She will be missed.
我们会怀念她的
And I suggest you bring backup. She can be a handful.
我建议你最好带上后援 她可相当棘手
Especially when cornered...
特别是被逼入绝境的时候…
Am I the only one here who considers this to be overkill on Lord Megatron's part?
难道只有我认为威震天在小题大作吗？
I mean, dispatching two of his most proficient warriors
我是说 他居然派遣两个得力部下
to track down one unconfirmed Energon spike.
去勘探一个未经开采的能量矿
Megatron knows me and Dreadwing here will get the job done.
威震天认为我和骇翼就足以完成任务
Actually, I was referring to Dreadwing and myself.
事实上 我说的得力部下是我和骇翼
Eghh...
呃…
Breakdown, remain on task.
打击 专注你的任务
This must be a unified effort.
我们必须齐心协力
Indeed, Breakdown.
没错 打击
I know we've never seen eyes to eye,
我知道你一只眼看不惯我一双眼
but that doesn't mean we can't patch things up.
不过你还有补丁嘛
That's it!
呃 受够了！
Don't!
别这样！
Breakdown, don't be a fool. Release me.
打击！别干傻事 先救我出来！
Hahahahaha...
哈哈哈
Easy prey.
小菜一碟…
Breakdown, what is your status? Breakdown!
打击 你怎么样了？打击!
MECH 1 to Silas. Our maneuvers have yielded unexpected results...
机械党一号报告塞拉斯 我们有了意外的发现
and a familiar face.
还是个老相识…
How is it that I have been reduced to seeking Energon scraps merely to survive?
我居然沦落到靠捡能量碎片来度日？
An Insecticon, on Earth?
机器昆虫？在地球上！
You there, scavenger!
嘿 你个捡垃圾的！
Deliver that Energon to me.
把那块能量给我
You dare turn your back on a superior life-form?
你胆敢对你的上司如此不敬？
I am commander Starscream.
我是红蜘蛛指挥官！
Fine! Keep the Energon.
好吧！留着那块能量吧！
I hope you choke on it.
希望它噎死你！
Yes, minion, approach me.
很好 奴隶 到我这儿来
Obey me.
服从我
Worship me.
朝拜我
You shouldn't have.
不用这么客气
What?! You reject a commander
什么？你拒绝了一个指挥官
but grovel at the feet of that wretch?
却对那种小人物奴颜婢膝？
Starscream. Don't get your turbines in a twist.
红蜘蛛 别愁眉苦脸的
After all, the beast and I are somewhat related.
毕竟 这个怪兽和我有些亲缘关系
You might even say we are of... one mind.
甚至可以说 我们是心灵相通的
Why are you here?
你为什么会在这儿？
Decepticons never return to stripped mines.
霸天虎从来不会回到开采完毕的矿区！
You are not the only rogue Decepticon in need of Energon.
你并非唯一一个回来找能量的流亡霸天虎
Was it a run-in with the Autobots?
那是和汽车人战斗受的伤？
Or did Megatron invite you on one of his field trips?
还是威震天又邀请你参加他的“实地考察”了？
Megatron was otherwise engaged.
威震天在忙别的事
But you should see his lackey.
不过你可以见到他的新仆人
You know, Airachnid,
你看 毒蜘蛛
as fellow outcasts, we should consider putting aside our differences.
我们同为流亡者 应先将分歧放在一边
With this creature under your control
我们有了这种听从你指挥的生物
... and at our disposal, we might employ it to terminate Megatron,
我们可以用他去了结威震天
allowing us to rule the Decepticons.
夺取霸天虎的控制权
Together?
一起？
We would simply need to lure Megatron here,
我们只需要将威震天引到这儿
away from his support systems,
让他远离他的“支援系统”
so that we might catch him...
这样我们也许能逮到他…
With his guard down?
趁他放松警惕之时？
An intriguing proposal...
一个迷人的计划
If ruling Decepticons or spending any length of time with you
不过我并不希望与你共同统治霸天虎
were of the slightest interest to me.
甚至是与你相处…
That... agh? huh!
什么？啊！
Of course, you had me at "terminate Megatron."
当然 你给了我一个打败威震天的机会
Payback would be sweet.
复仇会是甜蜜的…
However you wish to spin it.
总之你说了算
I would need to ensure my assassin is up to the task.
我需要确认我的刺客能胜任这份差事
Perhaps a test run is in order.
也许需要一个测试…
What? I thought we were partners.
什么？我以为我们是同伴！
Eviscerate him.
剖开他！
What is it?
这是什么？
A high-frequency signal with an embedded message.
一个含有嵌入信息的高频信号
Again?
又是他？
Starscream. "I have obtained information of extreme interest to you."
红蜘蛛 我有你最感兴趣的情报
"Bring medical kit."
带医疗箱过来
Clear!
安全！
Make it fast.
快说！
It would appear that, like myself, Airachnid has gone rogue.
毒蜘蛛也成了像我一样的流亡霸天虎
What's it to us?
这对我们有什么用？！
She is planning to retaliate against Meg...
她计划报复威…
Eh... mankind.
…人类！
I can provide you with her current location.
我可以向你提供她目前的位置
I don't believe you.
我不相信你
Why wouldn't you?
为什么？
I directed you to the location of the decepticon space bridge
我曾经告诉你霸天虎太空桥的位置
so you could rescue Orion Pax, didn't I?
你才救回了奥利安・派克斯 对吧？
Yeah, but then you helped M.E.C.H. steal Bumblebee's T-cog.
是的 但随后你就帮机械党偷走了大黄蜂的变形齿轮
So? He got it back, didn't he?
是吗？但他又抢了回去 不是吗？
I admit... aligning myself with those vile humans
我承认！与邪恶的人类合作
was a colossal error in judgment.
是个巨大的错误
But I am alone. I do what I must to survive.
但我孤立无援！我做的一切都是为了生存！
But I have paid the price.
而且我为此付出了代价
I am now the one missing his T-cog.
现在我失去了自己的变形齿轮！
You're grounded?
你飞不起来了？
Thus of little, if any, threat to you.
所以对你们来说毫无威胁
But Airachnid and her Insecticon intend to...
但是 毒蜘蛛和她的机器昆虫打算…
An Insecticon?! Here?
机器昆虫？！在这里？
How?
怎么会？！
Well, I would have asked.
本来我也想问个明白…
but I was too busy squeezing through a narrow crevice
…但当时我急于从一个小缝隙里面挤过去
trying to keep the vermin from chewing my leg off!
以防止那只毒虫啃掉我的腿！
While Airachnid watched.
而毒蜘蛛就在一旁看着…
The reason for our inability to locate Breakdown's signal is all too clear.
我们已经搞清了为什么无法定位打击的信号
But how is it that you were unable to recover his remains?
但为何你连他的残骸都没能带回来？
What is it?
那是什么？
Heard from Breakdown lately?
想听听打击的最新消息吗？
Trace the communication.
追踪信号
Megatron, truly.
亲爱的威震天
You sent simple henchman to terminate a high-ranking officer.
你居然派一个白痴喽罗 妄图消灭一个高级军官
I thought you reserved that honor for yourself.
我本以为你只会把这份殊荣留给自己…
Is that a challenge?
这是个挑衅！
An invitation.
一个邀请
And since Soundwave is no doubt tracing this signal
毫无疑问 既然声波正在追踪这个信号
you know where to find me.
那你知道在哪里能找到我…
I'll be back.
我去去就来
Allow me to accompany you.
请允许我伴您同去
You already had your chance.
我已经给过你机会了
The coordinates Starscream provided are within an abandoned Decepticon mine.
红蜘蛛提供的坐标位于一座废弃的霸天虎矿区
Hold on. You just fixed him up and sent him on his way?
等等 你刚刚修好他 就打发他走了？
What were we supposed to do?
不然你想怎么样
Take him back here?
带他回来？
Not that I wouldn't jump at any chance to put Airachnid down,
我不会放弃任何一个追杀毒蜘蛛的机会
but she isn't the only one who's robbed me of a partner.
但她并非唯一一个杀害我搭档的人
You weren't there, Arcee.
当时你不在场 阿尔茜
Starscream was weak, defenseless.
红蜘蛛虚弱至极 毫无抵抗能力
And learning of the Insecticon could prove highly tactical.
此外机器昆虫的情报具有战略价值
Starscream's intel has proved credible in the past.
根据以往的经验 红蜘蛛的情报是可靠的
Sure, when he wasn't busy stabbing us in the back.
没错！在他不忙于暗算我们的时候
Without the resources we possessed on Cybertron,
眼下我们缺少塞博特恩上的资源
we lack ready means of capturing and imprisoning our enemies.
用来监禁和束缚敌人
Nonetheless, I do not condone the termination of any defenseless life-form.
尽管如此 我仍然不能漠视无助的生命
You don't waste time.
您一向雷厉风行
Your stay of execution has come to an end.
你的缓刑期已经到头了！
I will leave you two to get acquainted.
我介绍你们俩认识一下
Bow before Megatron, your leader.
向威震天 你们的主人 鞠躬！
I said, "bow..."
我说 鞠躬！
You and your beast would do well to remember...
你和你的畜牲给我记住了
I honed my skills in the pits of Kaon!
我可是在卡隆的角斗场里杀出来的！
Proceed with extreme caution.
谨慎行事
Finish him!
结果他！
Whoa. Scream never mentioned Megatron.
喔 小红可没提到威震天！
It would seem Starscream orchestrated this convergence,
看上去是红蜘蛛精心策划了这一幕
in the hope that all his enemies would destroy each other on his behalf.
设计让他的敌人自相残杀 好坐收渔翁之利
And I fell for it.
我中计了！
Well, you can have whatever's left of Megatron. Airachnid's mine.
你可以随意处置威震天的遗骸 毒蜘蛛是我的
Arcee! No!
阿尔茜 不！
You.
你！
So many surprises, today.
今天真是惊喜连连！
Let that be a warning to anyone who dares cross a gladiator of Kaon,
这是一个警告 给所有妄图挑衅卡隆角斗士的人！
be they Decepticon...  or Autobot.
无论是霸天虎或是汽车人
It would seem that I'm unarmed and at your mercy.
我已经无力反抗了 全凭你处置
So, tell me, Optimus. Do you intend to take me alive?
请告诉我擎天柱 你会放我一马吗？
Or end this here and now?
或是就此了结恩怨
The surprises never cease.
惊喜总是不断
Oh, scrap.
哦 糟了…
Scrap!
不好!
This may not be the day that I take Megatron's spike,
或许今天我无法熄灭威震天的火种
but it is the day I remove yours.
但我可以结果了你…
How right you were, Airachnid.
你说的很对 毒蜘蛛
Payback is sweet.
复仇会是甜蜜的
Deliver Megatron to us,
把威震天交给我们
and I will allow you to live.
我们会让你们全身而退
Never trust a Con. Kick buckethead's bucket!
永远不要相信虎子 打爆这个铁桶头！
Dreadwing, do I have your word?
骇翼 我能信任你吗？
My liege.
我的君王
Dreadwing may have given you his word, but I did not.
骇翼 也许你会遵守诺言 可我不会
Destroy them!
消灭他们！
You disobeyed my orders in following me here.
你们胆敢抗命追踪我到此
You will make a fine first lieutenant.
你会是一个好副官的
That was intense.
这可真够刺激的
Now, if there's one thing I despise nearly as much as eight-leggers,
如果说除了八条腿的我还讨厌什么
it's two-wheelers.
那就是两轮车…
Go on. Get it over with.
来吧 动手吧
As I recollect, in a similar predicament.
我想起来了 这一幕似曾相识
you once allowed me to live.
你留了我一命
Consider us even.
现在我们扯平了
Arcee, what is your status?
阿尔茜 你情况如何？
In need of assist, but alive.
还活着 但需要帮助
And so is Airachnid.
估计毒蜘蛛也一样
At least Megatron took care of the other bug problem.
至少威震天除掉了她的害虫
Starscream, I vow I will have your head.
红蜘蛛 我发誓要拧下你的脑袋！
So, my warrior was merely a scout.
原来我的“战士”不过是个前哨！